# **Deshdeep Srivastava**

+91 80040 24993 | deshdeep.srivastava@outlook.com | linkedin.com/in/deshdeep-srivastava | github.com/deshdeep-srivastava

# **SUMMARY**

Developed a strong skill set in delivering projects and ensuring their proper functionality and reliability, backed by nearly 2 years of industry experience. Proficient in Python, SQL, MS Excel, and possess fundamental knowledge of R, essential for data analysis and visualization.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Programming Languages: Python, SQL, Power BI, R

Libraries & Tools: MS Excel, Tkinter, Pandas, BeautifulSoup, Git

## **PROJECTS**

#### **Cricket Scoreboard**

GUI based Project

Python, VS Code, Tkinter

- Developed an interactive GUI Scoreboard using Tkinter.
- · User need to input only a single value, either the run scored or a wicket fallen.
- · Implemented logic to calculate score changes based on user input.

#### Sales Dashboard

Power BI

Data Cleaning, Data Manipulation

- Developed an interactive sales dashboard for comprehensive data exploration and analysis.
- · Advanced parameters enable granular worksheet exploration with customized filters and slicers.
- · Established data connections, integrated tables, and implemented calculations for dynamic user-defined visualizations.

# **EXPERIENCE**

**Associate Consultant** 

Nov 2022 – Present Gurugram, Haryana

SHL India Pvt Ltd

- Conducted in-depth research and developed presentations using Power BI to support the creation of new question banks.
- Implemented new data standardization parameters, improving readability and consistency. This resulted in a 20% reduction in project review and improvement time.
- Executed SQL queries to insert and update QBs in the database.
- Developed and tested MS Office simulations, ensuring full quality accuracy by rectifying errors, and played a key role in finalizing over 200 simulation modules.
- Implemented a comprehensive QA review to identify and rectify any errors or omissions in the final questions prior to the test launch.

**Intern** Feb 2022 – June 2022

Surya InfoTech

Remote

- Leveraged collaborative coding to enhance banking security solutions.
- Utilized programming skills to proactively address and resolve project challenges, ensuring successful completion.

### **EDUCATION**

**KNIT Sultanpur** 

B. Tech in Electronics Engineering

affiliated to AKTU Lucknow Aug 2018 - May 2022

#### CERTIFICATIONS

- · Business Analysis Fundamentals Udemy
- Power BI SimpliLearn
- · Python Certificate HackerRank
- · Fundamentals of Database and SQL SimpliLearn